<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-22T03:42:02+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Mastering Typing</title><subtitle>Practice Typing Speed.</subtitle><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><entry><title type="html">What’s the most efficient way to learn touch type?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/whats-efficient-way-learn-touch-type/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What's the most efficient way to learn touch type?" /><published>2016-10-10T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-10-11T04:14:10+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/whats-efficient-way-learn-touch-type/whats-efficient-way-learn-touch-type</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/whats-efficient-way-learn-touch-type/index.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;Touch type is to type using all one's fingers and without looking at the keys.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-308&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/Yoast-fab-Origin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Break the rule, feel the keyboard through your fingers, freestyle touch type&quot; width=&quot;1200&quot; height=&quot;630&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Break the rule, feel the keyboard through your fingers, freestyle touch type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Touch type is one of the most important skill in today’s world both professionally &amp;amp; personally. It is a skill which can be learned when we are young, but it’s never too late to learn new things in life. It is a sure thing which can prove helpful in long run and definitely save a lots of time. Before learning this skill, I matched this skill with the skill of learning a bicycle. At first, you fall many times but after sometime the brain automatically learn this and day by day you become good in bicycle riding. Our brain takes sometime to develop a kind of pattern in it. Once the pattern is developed, it will be with you. Mark my words “Repetition Creates Memory” for your fingers. Sharp the memory better the typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here is some advise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mistakes are unavoidable, no one is perfect at the first time. So don’t try to aim for 0 mistakes because that’ll slow you down, due to the sheer speed that one types during touch typing, you’re gonna make some typo here and there eventually. That’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a certain period, try to type only on a single keyboard that you are comfortable with it ( and I suggest mechanical if you’d like to, it’s really good experience for typists). Use one keyboard a long time to helps you to remember exactly where each keys are located. Notice how different keyboards have slightly different keys and their relative position from each other depends on how the keyboard is designed. Once you can type really fast on that keyboard ( say 100 wpm or more), try and move to other keyboards and see whether you can type faster after some getting used to the keyboard layout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No need perfect to learn touch type, break the rules. There is some reason why you don’t need to follow the rules. because everyone has differently sized hands and fingers, asking everyone to follow and use certain fingers to hit certain keys is very limiting. Try to freestyle type and see whether you use the suggested fingers to hit the keys. If you don’t, it might be because your hands and fingers are differently sized from the norm or that your keyboard is designed slightly differently from the norm. Those issues are common so devise your own set of “muscle memory rules” that you can adhere to and you’ll be on your way to typing much faster than you would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typing the words, texts from the books or newspaper you like, could be your favorite words, quotes, transcript, songs, or anything else to motivate you practice typing. Or you could listen some music while you practice. Just relax and focus on practice typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s worthy to learn touch typing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Save time:&lt;/em&gt; It would help you to write your blogs, journal, messages, chatting etc. faster without wasting time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Impression:&lt;/em&gt; It will impress other people who don’t know this skill. They may say like, Wow! how can you do that and within mind they may be thinking if they could also type like you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pleasure:&lt;/em&gt; It is a pleasure to just focus on thinking and the typing is done automatically, no distraction from figuring out where the keys are located&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Job:&lt;/em&gt; Many jobs today ask for good typing speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">  Touch type is to type using all one's fingers and without looking at the keys. Break the rule, feel the keyboard through your fingers, freestyle touch type</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Refreshing Eyes Exercises at Computer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/refreshing-eye-exercises-computer/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Refreshing Eyes Exercises at Computer" /><published>2016-10-08T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-10-09T03:38:54+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/refreshing-eye-exercises-computer/refreshing-eye-exercises-computer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/refreshing-eye-exercises-computer/index.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staring at a computer screen all day long sure puts a strain on your eyes. Sitting in front of computer for so long is not only strenuous for our eyes but may also cause headaches and muscle tensions. We all know that we need to relax our eyes while working on the computer but we either just don’t care or we just don’t know how to take care of our eyes. We can learn to relax our eyes while sitting on the computer using these tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-287 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/Computer-Relax.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Refresh your eye&quot; width=&quot;674&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Refresh your eyes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blink your eyes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since a lack of blinking is one of the contributing factors to computer-induced eyestrain, as it dries your eyes and causes scratchiness, it’s very important to blink. You may have to train yourself to blink normally while sitting in front of computer. It relaxes them by providing moisture to the eyes. So blink as often as possible to prevent your eyes from drying out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roll your eyes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close your eyes, roll your eyes around in circular motions to relax eye muscles and deep breathe for 1 minute every hour. This helps to lubricate your eyes and eases the strain on the muscles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glancing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes a glance is more than just a glance! Start this one with your eyes closed while sitting. Keep your eyes closed as you glance up as far as comfortably possible. Hold for a moment, then look down. Repeat a few times and then take an eye-breather (open your eyes and look around). Next, close your eyes again. Now, keeping your eyes closed like before, look to the right and the left. Repeat this a few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Close your eyes every 20 minutes. Relax your eyes after every 20 minutes by closing them. Rub your palms and place them lightly on your eye lids for about 30 seconds. Now, take your hands and press them over your (closed) eyes. Put your left hand on your left eye and right hand on your right eye. Let the heat warm your eyes and relax for a few minutes like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take a break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a 5 minute break every hour. Get up from the chair, have a cookie or a glass of water. Stretch a little. Just get away from the computer. It will not only give your eyes a refreshing break but also give your body and mind a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The proper monitor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adjust the distance of your monitor. If you can still touch your monitor with your arm stretched out while you are leaning back in your chair, you should move your monitor backwards a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use an anti-glare screen on your computer. This screen protects your eyes from the radiations coming out of the computer or laptop screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The font size at your monitor should be big enough so you can easily read from a normal sitting position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use some software to remind you&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EyeLeo -  http://eyeleo.com/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EyesRelax -&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By doing a few of these exercises like the ones above and taking a daily eye vitamin, you may increase your productivity, eliminate headaches and work errors, and maybe even reduce your risk of glaucoma! When you stop and think about what you gain by following these simple exercises there is really no reason not to give them a try. Work and school can be difficult enough without straining your eyes and giving yourself more of a headache then necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html"> </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fun Facts about QWERTY and Typewriter</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/fun-facts-qwerty-typewriter/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fun Facts about QWERTY and Typewriter" /><published>2016-10-07T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-10-08T02:06:47+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/fun-facts-qwerty-typewriter/fun-facts-qwerty-typewriter</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/fun-facts-qwerty-typewriter/index.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-283&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/typewriter1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Typewriter&quot; width=&quot;765&quot; height=&quot;628&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Typewriter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s some interesting facts about QWERTY and Typewriter, not just our standard QWERTY keyboard, but we also look at some of the other types out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;The Typewriter and computers today use the same key layout.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Most modern keyboards use the &quot;qwerty&quot; layout.  This name comes from the first five letters on the top row.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;The qwerty layout was designed for manual typewriters initially by Christopher Sholes all the way back in 1868.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;The QWERTY keyboard was designed in 1873 to put common letter pairs far apart to reduce the chance of keys jamming and raise typing speed.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Most early typewriter would have a bell to warn the typist that the were nearing the end of the paper.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;According to Mark Twain, his “Tom Sawyer” in 1876 was the first novel written on a typewriter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;The word 'typewriter' can be typed entirely using the top row of keys. It has been speculated that this may have been a factor in the choice of keys for ease of demonstration.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;The longest word that could be types only the left hand is 'stewardesses'.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;The longest words that can be typed using only the right hand in proper typing form are ”lollipop” and “monopoly”.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;'Skepticisms' is the longest word that alternates hands when typing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;The QWERTY layout was never changed when computers started hitting the market. Secretaries and people using typewriters were used to the old layout and even when other, more efficient layouts, have been proven effective, the old layout has remained with us, and will for many years.&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;DVORAK'S unsuccessful layout, in 1932 Professor August Dvorak attempted to make the ultimate keyboard that would be easier to use than QWERTY. What an odd name as well, August? He wasn’t even born in August! I’m jealous. Anyway Dvorak’s idea to make it better than the original was by arranging the letters according to frequency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">Typewriter</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What jobs that require typing skills?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/jobs-require-typing-skills/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What jobs that require typing skills?" /><published>2016-10-05T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-10-05T23:41:29+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/jobs-require-typing-skills/jobs-require-typing-skills</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/jobs-require-typing-skills/index.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typing skills is advantage, as technology becomes more commonplace in the workforce, therefore most jobs require at least the most basic typing skills. In fact, many employers are requiring candidates to be able to type at least a minimum of 35 wpm just for the sake of productivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-273&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/Data-Entry-Jobs-simple-typing-job.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Typing skills&quot; width=&quot;494&quot; height=&quot;394&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Typing skills&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Data Entry (Excel, or spreadsheet)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data entry is simply taking data provided by a company and entering it into some sort of system or spreadsheet. This could be entering payroll items into a system for employers, catalog items into a system for retailers, and compiling lists of customer interactions for businesses, just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employers that hire people for data-entry positions usually look for applicants who can type between 60 and 80wpm. They want people who can enter data quickly so that they can input more information in a shorter amount of time. Along with speed, you’ll need to be accurate as you enter information into the computer system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Word Processors (Word, PDF, document)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The position of word processors or typists requires the typist to accurately type 55 to 90 words per minute. This is an excellent opportunity for people who can type fast. The job usually requires an individual to convert hand written documents into digital copies by typing them manually on the computer. Documents can range anything from reports, meeting minutes or correspondence material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Transcription (Subtitle, create script from recording)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transcription is another type of work from home job that is interchangeably used with data entry and typing jobs. At the most basic level transcription is simply typing audio versions of documents. This could be lectures, workshops, conference calls, podcasts, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transcriptionists are required to have fast typing speed and excellent listening skills. The job demands the individual to write simultaneously with audio recordings while maintaining maximum accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Translation (From foreign language to native language)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Translators are required to have an in depth knowledge about the English language and the language they will be translating from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Journalism/General Writing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast typing and reading skills benefit journalists, writers, authors and reporters significantly. It helps the individuals create reports and articles quickly and efficiently. Given that the field of journalism and general writing depend a lot on meeting short deadlines, fast typing skills can enable them to meet these deadlines without pulling too much effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software/Web/Application Developers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web languages, software coders or web developers are required to have fast typing skills with considerable accuracy. Fast typing skills enables the developer to create codes quickly and efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Legal Transcriptionists&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike general transcriptionists, legal transcriptionists work exclusively on legal documents. They are responsible for creating documents required by paralegals, attorneys and anyone else in the legal department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Court Reporter&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A court reporter needs to catch every word that is said during a court proceeding. This means that he or she needs to be able to type incredibly fast, around 225wpm. To achieve this, court reporters use special typing machines called stenotype machines. The keys on these machines are laid out differently than they are on a QWERTY keyboard, which is the standard computer keyboard layout. Court reporters go through special training to learn how to achieve such fast typing speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Finally, typing skills is advantage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if work in a profession that doesn’t require you to have a minimum typing speed, it can be to your advantage to be able to type quickly. Having typing skills can help you accomplish your work more effectively when you do need to type. Having a fast typing speed can also make you more marketable in the job field.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html"> </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How many ways to improve typing speed?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/many-ways-practice-typing-speed/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How many ways to improve typing speed?" /><published>2016-10-03T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-10-03T09:16:41+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/many-ways-practice-typing-speed/many-ways-practice-typing-speed</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/many-ways-practice-typing-speed/index.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the technology for teaching typing speed skills hasn’t improved much since back then, although you can now take a simple typing speed test online. The various typing test online from game, to race, to simple typing to help to improve your typing speed. But how many ways are there to help you improve typing speed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-233&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/typing-speed.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Typing Speed&quot; width=&quot;460&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Typing Speed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some way to improve your typing speed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first is most popular source now is to chat with friends&lt;/strong&gt;, fb messager, skype chat. We often chat a lot with friends via Facebook or gamming, or write a comment on forums. The simple words often in lower case, something it mix in with abbreviation and or special character to reduce the words, to type faster. It might be the way for you to practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second one is working environment&lt;/strong&gt;, writing the report, prepare the slide for demo, or write the formal email with punctuation, full words and no abbreviation. You have to write a lot and it’s really boring, we all often want to type fast to go home soon, this source often put the pressure on us to force typing faster. Not only just typing faster but also have to think what to write. This one might be other way to practice typing speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third, blogger type a lot, the writer write ideas on paper.&lt;/strong&gt; These people really need typing speed, to capture the spark of ideas, or lose it. Maybe there some deadline on their work that force them to increase their speed. The environment is key factor to increase their speed without practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finally&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the ways I list above is not really good way to improve typing because of multiple tasking, thinking, and interrupting. It might increase their speed typing but it will take a long time to fast typing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is the better way to increase your typing speed in the short period, one thing at a time, laser focus on practice, practice, and practice typing without thinking about other things, or interrupt by other work. Copy your own favorite texts, and practice regularly it, each day just a few minutes can achieve the huge outcomes. Practice now with &lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;MasteringTyping.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;MasteringTyping.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html"> </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Do programmers required to be fast typist?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/programmers-required-fast-typists/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do programmers required to be fast typist?" /><published>2016-09-26T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-09-27T05:17:50+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/programmers-required-fast-typists/programmers-required-fast-typists</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/programmers-required-fast-typists/index.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-266&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/Why-do-need-to-be-fast-typists-troll-face.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Why do you need to be fast typist?&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Why do you need to be fast typist?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fast typist isn’t necessary, but it wouldn’t hurt to be able to type “naturally” using all your fingers, without needing to hunt and peck, as needing to find characters on the keyboard can be distracting and may interrupt your train of thoughts. (Programming is all about thinking logic and how to translate you thought in to machine languages). Do you really want to waste time and brainpower looking for keys rather than letting your fingers move to the keys automatically?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More productivity on works&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;“If I had eight hours to chop down a tree, I’d spend six hours sharpening my ax.”  - Abraham Lincoln&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll have to spend some number of hours practicing and you’ll have a few weeks or even months of lowered productivity, but after an uncomfortable and hard time early period you’ll be benefits for the rest of your life. It will make your life easier permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you learn to touch type, you will find that your code will move from your brain to the screen much faster. You won’t have to think about where your fingers are or move your hands or eyes around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fast typing is not necessary per se, but it is an advantage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a year in programming with my colleague. I heard the story they often told “Why do I need to typing faster or use all the fingers when I’ve already have Auto Complete in my IDE? (Typing few keyword and press Tab, done. That’s it.)”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is that really you just programming for the rest of your life without typing anything else, like write the long document, the report, response the emails, or chatting with customer to explain something in urgent situation like software assistant (Do you really want people other side wait for long response from you?). Or could be one day you write the blogs :). I know the habit is really difficult to change, but just set aside a few minutes a day to practice, in the long run, you will be benefits a lot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Final thought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the crucial skill for programmers. It’s not necessary, it’s a skill you should acquire for your sake in the long term. For early periods as a developer, programming slow my typing speed down on special characters ({} . $this-&amp;gt;, $, _/), but through the practice every day, I see it bring much benefits, not just speed typing on programming, but also chatting with other customers, write document and other works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;MasteringTyping.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html"> </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Is that true wpm measures the speed of typing?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/wpm-measures-speed-typing/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Is that true wpm measures the speed of typing?" /><published>2016-09-16T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-09-16T07:48:11+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/wpm-measures-speed-typing/wpm-measures-speed-typing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/wpm-measures-speed-typing/index.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been researched a lot through forums, websites about wpm. And I heard a lot of people want to reach to 100 (wpm), or from 100 (wpm) to 150 (wpm). But what is words per minute anyway? Is that factor really measures your typing speed as we often thought?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Fact about WPM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-228&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/wpm-key.png&quot; alt=&quot;wpm&quot; width=&quot;620&quot; height=&quot;279&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; WPM factor&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people often think that typing speed is measured in words per minute ( wpm ). Since words are not all the same it would not be fair to measure someone’s typing speed counting the actual number of words taken randomly. Consider the following cases:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Simple words that all text is lower case. (often use in chatting with friends or colleague)&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Complex words from history, or poem, or lyrics, or transcript. (For writer, blogger, writing report)&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Words with punctuation and capitals. (often meet in the reality)&lt;/li&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;Words from programming with a lot of special characters. (!@#$%^&amp;amp;*).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each case, even they have the same number of words, but I can pretty sure that words per minute factor will different for each case if you take a test. Why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Simple words that all text is lower case&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of website take a test with lower case, the easy one, right? So all you have to do is move your fingers around the 26 character on the keyboard without hold and press the Shift or reach higher row on the top (the number 1, 2, 3, …). That’s why your speed might be look pretty good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Complex words from history, or poem, or transcript, etc&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how about the test with complex word from history, or lyrics, poem, in the case 2. You speed will slow down a little bit even with the lower case. And one more thing from my experience, if you practice with one text over and over, your speed will increase, but if you change to another text different, you speed go down a little bit compare with the text you practice before. It’s just normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Words with punctuation and capitals.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speed is go down a little, if we hold press Shift + other characters, include . and , ; write the name of someone, or type report. And you will see 100 (wpm) with all lower is different with 100 wpm with mix punctuation and capitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
 	&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Words from programming with a lot of special characters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For developer, and programmer, this is really hard to increase their speed. They often use all the key in keyboard, from Tab, Shift, Home, Del, Ins, other special char {}:”, it’s really hard to keep the speed typing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you take test from various website, and your speed various around 100 wpm. No worry about that, because the text you taken is different, all lower case, or include the punctuation with capitals, something it could include special characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, I think the words per minute factor is relatively measure your speed typing, not absolute exactly 100 wpm. Just around that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;MasteringTyping.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html"> </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Keyswitch in Mechanical Keyboard Guide</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/keyswitch-mechanical-keyboard-guide/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keyswitch in Mechanical Keyboard Guide" /><published>2016-09-11T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-09-12T05:30:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/keyswitch-mechanical-keyboard-guide/keyswitch-mechanical-keyboard-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/keyswitch-mechanical-keyboard-guide/index.html">&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A keyswitch is &lt;em&gt;tactile&lt;/em&gt; if it has a bump in its response to finger pressure at or near the engagement point where the keypress registers and &lt;em&gt;before&lt;/em&gt; the key bottoms out at the end of its travel. A keyboard is tactile if it is made with tactile keyswitches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Terms&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Travel:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;The trajectory of a keyswitch from the top (when a finger begins pressing) to the bottom when it reaches its mechanical limit. Travel distance is usually between 2 and 5 mm.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Linear:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;The opposite of tactile. A linear keyswitch produces constant resistance until it stops at the end of its travel.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Stiffness:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Proportional to the force required to push a keyswitch from top of travel to its engagement point.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Island keys:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;A style of keyboard in which formed keycaps protrude through a perforated metal or plastic plate, rather than simply abutting each other separated by a very small gap. Recent Apple keyboards are like this. The term &quot;chiclet keyboard&quot; is sometimes incorrectly used for these.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Clicky:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;A clicky keyswitch produces audible as well as tactile feel at its engagement point. Clicky keyboards are made from clicky keyswitches. All clicky keyboards are tactile, but not vice-versa. (We contemptuously ignore a few exceptions that electronically simulate a click using a speaker.)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Silent:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;The opposite of &lt;em&gt;clicky&lt;/em&gt;. A silent keyswitch may produce some noise when the key bottoms out, but generates none at the engagement point.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;Keyswitch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Dome switch:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;A very common, very cheap style of keyswitch consisting of a hollow rubber or metalized dome with contacts at the top and bottom that meet when the dome is compressed by finger pressure. Usually manufactured in arrays in a formed rubber sheet. Silent and linear, low stiffness. Most modern keyboards use these. Tactile-keyboard fans despise them.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Scissor switch:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Shorter-travel variant of the dome switch often found on low-profile keyboards such as most of Apple’s. So called because the keycap is connected to the dome by a plunger cradled by two pieces of plastic that are hinged together like scissors blades. Tactile-keyboard fans often find these somewhat less nasty than bare dome switches.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Mechanical switch:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;A keyswitch with a mechanical plunger assembly, springs, and contacts. All tactile and clicky keyswitches are mechanical, but not vice-versa. Mechanical switches are more durable than dome switches, often surviving multiple decades of heavy use. They are also (alas) much more expensive.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Buckling-spring switch:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;The creme de la creme of mechanical keyswitches, found only on the IBM Model M and close relatives such as the modern Unicomp. Tactile &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; clicky_ with a relatively long travel; too noisy and stiff for some tastes, but the unique feel and sound inspires near-fanatical devotion in its fans.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Cherry switch:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;A brand name for the most widely used line of mechanical keyswitch. Several different Cherry variants are named for colors (with the switch casings actually in that color) and offer different stiffnesses and combinations of tactile/linear/clicky/silent behaviors. Cherry Blues and Greens are tactile-clicky and generally considered the closest in feel to buckling-spring switches. There was an earlier Cherry White, now rare, that was also tactile-clicky. Cherry Browns, Clears, and Greys are tactile-silent.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Keyboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Membrane keyboard:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;This is what the keypad on your microwave oven uses. Linear, silent, less than a millimeter of travel, effectively zero stiffness. Never found on real keyboards.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Chiclet keyboard:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;A variant of the membrane keyboard in which the keys are chiclet-shaped rubber nibs bonded to the upper membrane. Even people who like dome-switch keyboards usually consider these shoddy and nasty; they’re not deployed unless lowest cost is absolutely imperative. In recent years this term has sometimes been misapplied to any low-profile keyboard with island keys.&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Ergonomic keyboard:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10pt;&quot;&gt;Loosely used for keyboard layouts and case designs that try to support support a more natural, relaxed position of the hands and arms than allowed by the conventional rectangular QWERTY design. Ergonomic keyboards may be split or angled in various creative ways, or arrange keys in arcs better fitting the hand’s range of motion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Cherry MX Switches&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a variety of switch constructions for these types of keys, and they can be differentiated by the color of the stem, which you can see when you remove the keycap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linear Switch: Cherry MX Black&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actuation Force: 60cN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-222&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/CherryMXBlack.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Linear Switch: Cherry MX Black&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt; Linear Switch: Cherry MX Black&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cherry MX Black switches were one of the first mechanical keyboard switches available to the general public. They are linear, or non-tactile, this means that Black switches don’t have a loud click or a bump that is felt when a key is depressed. Many gamers like these because of the smooth feel and the fact that the actuation and release points are at the exact same position, making double tapping easier than other switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light Tactile Switch: Cherry MX Brown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actuation Force: 55cN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-221&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/CherryMXBrown.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Light Tactile Switch: Cherry MX Brown&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Light Tactile Switch: Cherry MX Brown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Brown switches are about halfway between a typing and a gaming switch. Unlike the black switches, the browns have a soft, tactile bump about halfway through the key press. Some people prefer them for gaming since it enables you to double tap faster and typists like them because they still have a good tactile feedback, but the audio feedback isn’t quite as noticeable as Blue switch. The Brown switches have a softer click when depressed and require less force to actuate. The Das Keyboard tactile-soft series utilizes Brown switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clicky Switch: Cherry MX Blue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actuation Force: 60cN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-220 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/CherryMXBlue.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Clicky Keyswitch: Cherry MX Blue&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt; Clicky Switch: Cherry MX Blue&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Blue switches are popular within the typing community because of the “clicky” tactile bump when the activation point is hit. The overall experience of Blue switches is very similar to typewriters, however, those around you might not be as big of a fan due to the audio feedback. The standard “clicky” versions of Das Keyboards utilize Blue switches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Light Tactile Switch: Cherry MX Clear&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actuation Force: 65cN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-218&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/CherryMXClear.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Light Tactile Switch: Cherry MX Clear&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Light Tactile Switch: Cherry MX Clear&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cherry MX Clear switches are a bit harder to find in keyboards, but many users consider them to have more of a tactile feel than the Browns without being as clicky as the Blue switches. The clear switches have a higher actuation force than the Brown switches and a more pronounced tactile bump. Also, Clears tend to have the most friction among mechanical key switches, this is due to the size of the tactile bump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linear Switch: Cherry MX Red&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actuation Force: 45cN&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-219&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/CherryMXRed.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Linear Switch: Cherry MX Red&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; /&gt; &lt;em&gt;Linear Switch: Cherry MX Red&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cherry MX Red switches are similar to the Cherry MX Blacks in that they are both categorized as linear, non-tactile. This means that their feel remains constant through each up-down key stroke. Where they differ from the Black switches is in their resistance; Red switches require less force to actuate. The result is a feel that most perceive as “smoother” and “faster,” making them especially popular among gaming enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html"> </summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to properly sit in front of a computer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/properly-sit-front-computer/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to properly sit in front of a computer" /><published>2016-09-08T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-09-08T20:17:12+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/properly-sit-front-computer/properly-sit-front-computer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/properly-sit-front-computer/index.html">&lt;h1&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-212&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/Most-common-pain.png&quot; alt=&quot;most-common-pain&quot; width=&quot;608&quot; height=&quot;239&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Most Common Pain&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting at your computer for any period of time can be a very exhausting even painful experience, fixating on a computer screen fatigues by overriding natural reflexes that coordinate and align posture, properly sit. And too many workplace injuries that could be avoided, prevention is always the better option than cure. This is a checklist to that you can carry out at your workstation, to make sure you’re comfortable, safe and productive at the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Terms:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Workplace Ergonomics is generally the optimization of the workplace so that the bodily harm is reduced. This is achieved by providing properly sit, lighting, ventilation and by providing stuff that places less stress on body. In case of computers, it is the chair, desk, computer keyboard and mouse etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-204&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/Ergonomic-Sitting-Position-Best-PC-Gaming-Chairs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Properly sit&quot; width=&quot;497&quot; height=&quot;425&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Properly sit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Back Rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-208&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/back-rest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;back-rest&quot; width=&quot;299&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Back rest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most common problem among people working for long time on computers is the lower back pain. This generates over time and is hard to treat, making people dependent on pain killers etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid this, use a chair that is adjustable. The slant of back of the chair should be around 100 to 110 percent. 90 percent is too straight and won’t be of any comfort. More than 125 percent will place stress on other parts of body – neck and eyes especially. 100 to 110 percent is ideal to keep the back problems away – provided you rest your entire back on the chair back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Properly Sit on a Flat Chair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most chairs are not designed for sitting rather they are designed for appearance and for stacking. Ergonomically designed chairs are often just band-aid efforts to release tension that is already created from poor positioning. Many of the ergonomically designed chairs do not solve the problem where it originates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose a chair with a firm flat seat. If your chair has a hollow or bucket type of seat modify the chair using a firm solid pillow or folded blanket placed in the hollow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Properly Sit with Your Weight in Front of Sits Bones&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-209&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/IntralingoPostureforTranslation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Don't slouch&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;184&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Don’t slouch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people sit behind the pelvic sits bones (ischial tuberosites) curling the pelvis under thus rounding the lower back and causing the neck and head to forward thrust. If you do not sense your sits bones than find them with your fingers. Lift up your butt and pull your butt muscles away behind you, then sit down slightly in front of the round bones (you can feel that are under your butt).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Keep Your Feet on the Floor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although changing leg positions can be very helpful in reducing the fatigue that comes with stillness its helpful to have your feet placed firmly on the ground. Doing so provides an energetic grounding as well as aiding structural stability. The nerves of the feet help stabilize and co-ordinate posture. Energetically the psoas muscle is the grounding wire of the human electrical system. This energy is translated from the psoas through the legs and needs to be received into the ground. Staying grounded helps reduce fatigue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Arm Rest and Shoulders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-206&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/arm-rest.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;arms-rest&quot; width=&quot;316&quot; height=&quot;316&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Arms rest and shoulders&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the chair has arm rest, use them so that the pressure on shoulders is reduced. On chairs without arm rest, the entire pressure is placed on shoulders. If you cannot buy a chair with arm rest, you can place your elbows on legs after crossing them. But this workaround of crossing legs and placing elbows on the legs can also be dangerous in long run. It is okay for short periods. Remember that if you keep the legs crossed (like resting one foot on the knee of other leg), blood flow to the legs will be affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid problems to legs and to care for your shoulders, use a chair with arm rests. If the arm rests are adjustable, it is even better because one size does not fit all. If you don’t have a chair with arm rest, try to buy one as soon as possible. You won’t want to live with shoulder pain all your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wrist Rest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot; wp-image-205&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/Wirst-rest-mouse-and-keyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Wrist rest mouse and keyboard&quot; width=&quot;372&quot; height=&quot;277&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Wrist rest - mouse and keyboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When talking about correct posture to properly sit in front of computer, it is important to note the position of wrists. The basic thing is to provide a rest to the wrists. Many of us keep on typing with wrists in the air. This practice places too much stress on wrists and if continued for longer periods, will cause permanent wrist pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If yours is a laptop, it comes with wrist rest on either side of touchpad. If you are using regular keyboards, there are many keyboards that are based on ergonomics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have an ergonomic keyboard, every fifteen minutes, rest your wrists placing the hands on legs or somewhere comfortable for a minute or two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Neck and Eyes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-207 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/blinking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;blinking&quot; width=&quot;350&quot; height=&quot;234&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Blink eyes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To prevent illness, you should be looking down at the screen. Do not be seated in a position where you have to pull your neck up and strain the muscles. Do not use a position that makes you look above the straight line of vision (a straight line would mean using eyes in the front without raising them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the above, it is recommended that you move away from the computer at regular intervals. While on computer, people forget to &lt;strong&gt;blink&lt;/strong&gt; – which increases the stress on the retina. This should never be taken lightly as it can cause blindness. There are third party programs available that remind you to take a break from staring at the screen like EyeLeo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In short, when we talk about correct posture to properly sit in front of computer, we are talking about ergonomics: the practice of avoiding discomfort to any part of your body. Your back, legs, neck and feet should be properly rested. Your eyes should keep on blinking and look either straight or a bit lower at the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;page-title&quot; class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">Most Common Pain</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Quick Brown Fox – Typing Technique for Beginner</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tech/quick-brown-fox-typing-technique/index.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Quick Brown Fox – Typing Technique for Beginner" /><published>2016-09-06T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2016-09-06T09:22:45+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tech/quick-brown-fox-typing-technique/quick-brown-fox-typing-technique</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tech/quick-brown-fox-typing-technique/index.html">&lt;h2&gt;Typing Technique for Beginner&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This typing technique is applied for beginner only, used to remember the keyboard layout if you’ve already known how to typing. Skip this article and find other challenge typing texts at &lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;MasteringTyping.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fastest way to type is to touch type (type without looking at the keyboard) with all 10 fingers. Period. If you are a 2, 4 or 6 finger hunt-and-pecker, this is where it ends. By following those simple steps, you will be on your way to touch typing at 50 to 100+ words per minute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Home Row&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-198&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/home_row_keyboard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Home Row - Typing Technique&quot; width=&quot;390&quot; height=&quot;242&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Home Row - Typing Technique&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The starting position for your fingers is called the home row. This is where your fingers live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fingers on your left hand go on the A, S, D &amp;amp; F keys, while the fingers on your right hand go on the J, K, L &amp;amp; ; keys. Both of your thumbs should rest on the big space bar at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Key Assignments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-199 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/assets/uploads/2016/10/key_assignment.png&quot; alt=&quot;key_assignment&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Key Assigment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, you have to memorize which fingers are responsible for the other keys. But, don’t worry, it’s really easy to remember. Each finger is responsible for the keys directly above and below it. In addition, the index fingers are also responsible for the keys directly beside it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Quick Brown Fox&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s something very special about this particular sentence. Can you guess what it is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog” is an English-language pangram—a phrase that contains all of the letters of the alphabet. It is commonly used for touch-typing practice. It is also used to test typewriters and computer keyboards, show fonts, and other applications involving all of the letters in the English alphabet. Owing to its brevity and coherence, it has become widely known.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes it the perfect sentence for learning how to touch type. By focusing on mastering typing just one sentence, you are taking the fastest route towards establishing touch typing muscle memory for your fingers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Practice &amp;amp; Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this method, practicing and reviewing is incredibly simple. Just go to homepage &lt;a href=&quot;https://masteringtyping.com/&quot;&gt;MasteringTyping.com&lt;/a&gt; and choose the text “The Quick Brown Fox” start typing the texts over and over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easy technique is that it clearly identifies which keys you’re having trouble with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s okay to look at the keyboard for the first time while, but you should quickly develop muscle memory making and be able to type the sentence while looking at the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Nguyen</name></author><summary type="html">Typing Technique for Beginner This typing technique is applied for beginner only, used to remember the keyboard layout if you’ve already known how to typing. Skip this article and find other challenge typing texts at MasteringTyping.com</summary></entry></feed>